MIKE WEST >> Hello, Internet!
Welcome to Web Accessibility.
Over the next few minutes, I'd like to explain
why form elements require labels.
Let's dive right in.
If I give you an arbitrary `input` element
of type `text`, you don't actually have enough
information to determine what you should start
typing.
Even if you know that the form in which the
element lives is requesting a mailing address,
it's difficult to guess as to whether a specific
field is requesting your name, your street
address, your zip code, or something else
entirely.
You need some additional context.
Visually, we solve this problem via layout,
and by positioning textual labels next to
the form fields.
I _see_ "name" next to the field, so I know
I should type my name.
Users who can't see the label, however, are
apt to be confused.
Let's take a look at a naïve implementation
of this labeling and determine how we can
improve it.
What we have here is a name (label), and an
input field.
If we run this through a screen reader, let's
see how it sounds.
CHROMEVOX >> Edit text.
MIKE WEST >> "Edit text."
That doesn't actually give me any context.
It doesn't give me information that I would
need in order to figure out what it is that
I should start typing here.
We have, however, this label, and it would
be great if we could somehow semantically
bind this text to the field.
In fact, HTML allows us to do exactly that
with the `label` element.
The first thing we're going to need to do
is uniquely identify this input field so that
we can say "Label X is associated with input
field Y."
We do that with an ID.
Great.
So now the input field has an ID, and we can
use that ID to label it.
We'll use the `label` element, and set a `for`
attribute that contains the same value as
the ID that we've just set.
Alright.
Let's run this through a screen reader, and
see how it sounds.
CHROMEVOX >> [Beep] Name.
Edit text.
MIKE WEST >> "Name.
Edit text."
That's excellent!
That gives us the context that we need in
order to start doing something useful with
this form field.
If we want to give them even more information,
for example, a, an example of text that I
should type here, we can use the `placeholder`
attribute, which is gaining support.
It's part of HTML5, it's not yet supported
by all screen readers, but most assistive
technology will pick it up at some point in
the near future.
Setting a `placeholder` [attribute] gives
me some visual feedback that there's something
interesting about this field.
It gives me a hint as to what it is that I
should start typing.
A screen reader like ChromeVox understands
this, and will read it out to a user.
Let's see how that sounds.
CHROMEVOX >> [Beep] Name.
With hint.
First and last name.
Edit text.
MIKE WEST >> "Name.
With hint.
First and last name.
Edit text."
So it tells me that I'm in an edit field,
that it has a label, of "Name" and that I
should type both my first and last name.
This is perfect.
For further discussion of accessibility on
the web, come visit us, at W one five Y dot
com.
That's W fifteen Y dot com.
Thanks for your time.